Surgical Research Society Minutes and Records,
Surgical Research Society Minutes and Records
1915-1946
Surgical Research Society
.4 linear feet (1 box)
Mss.arc
New York Academy of Medicine Library. Rare Book Room.
Historical Note
The Surgical Research Society was formed in 1915. In its early years, meetings were held biannually, but later a system of two day yearly meetings was adopted. Members hailed from Baltimore, Boston, Philadelphia, and New York City, as well as other cities on a case by case basis. Meetings were held in these cities, with the chosen city's members acting as host.
Scope and Content
This small collection primarily contains minutes, meeting programs, correspondence, membership lists, and other records of the Society. A letter concerning the transfer of these records to the New York Academy of Medicine is also included.
Arrangement of Collection
The records are arranged chronologically.
Index Terms
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the catalog of The New York Academy of Medicine Library. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Medicine -- Societies, etc.; Surgery -- Societies, etc.; Surgical Research Society.
Container List
- Surgical Research Society Minutes and Records
  - 1915-1927 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1928 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1928-1929 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1930-1931 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1932 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1933 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1934 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1935 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1936 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1937-1941 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Accession Letter, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 11)
Provenance
On deposit by the Surgical Research Society.